潜  龙  轰  天  Ⅰ
Pearl Harbor outer marker 30 minutes.
三十分钟后抵达珍珠港
Hey Case!
嗨  凯斯
What's happening?
什么？
Where's your whites? The Prez is coming.
制服呢？  老总快到了
He won't miss me.
不缺我一个的
What's this? You're in the Navy you've got to look good.
这什么德性？  你是海军  耍帅
- Cue Ball! - Where's your whites?
- 裘宝  你好  - 制服呢？
- Poor boy doesn't have a dress uniform. - I've got the dress I forgot the pumps.
- 可怜你没有裙装  - 我有  忘了带啦啦球而已
Tell him not to worry. Everything here is handled.
叫他别耽心  没问题的
Oh my God.
噢  我的天
No no that's okay. We'll take care of it.
没关系  我们会处理
Well it's going to be a zoo.
嗯  场面可有得瞧了！
Chief Ryback.
大厨雷白来了
Send him in.
请他进来
Get in your dress uniform.
穿上你的制服吧
You know how I feel about ceremonies. I thought this time...
你知道我很在乎礼节  我想...
If I had your ribbons I'd wear them to bed.
有你的杠和花的话  我一定穿
Yes sir.
是  长官
Get in your whites. I'll introduce you to the President.
换上制服我就带你去见总统
- I appreciate that but... - That's not a good idea.
- 谢了  不过...  - 这不是一个好主意
For once Commander Krill and I are in total agreement.
我和副舰长总算看法一致
I have 50 gallons of bouillabaisse I need to prepare by tomorrow.
我得在明天以前做出50锅汤
- My birthday? - I could do the cheeseburger routine.
- 是为我的生日？  - 是啊  不然要我做汉堡更简单
It's not for me it's the crew. They really love that stuff.
不  让弟兄们好好吃一顿
Just don't show your face till after the ceremony.
- 典礼完你再出现  - 是  长官
You're a sorry - looking sailor.
你是位服装不整的海军
That I am. Thank you sir.
我同意  谢谢长官指教
Sir...
长官...
... why do you tolerate that clown?
你为什么容忍那家伙？
I know he's a good cook...
就凭他烧一手好菜吗？
He's more than a good cook. You have no idea. Now let him be XO.
他是块料  你不懂的  随他去
Yes sir.
是  长官
Fifty years ago today...
五十年前的今天
... the infamous Japanese attack destroyed the Pacific fleet...
日本攻击并毁灭太平洋舰队
... here in Pearl Harbor.
地点就在珍珠港
In honor of those who died the USS Missouri now returns.
为向死者致敬  密舰重返旧地
Built to avenge Pearl Harbor she did.
它完成保卫珍珠港的使命
Days after we dropped the bomb on Hiroshima...
于广岛投下原子弹的数天后
... Japan surrendered on the Missouri's deck...
日本于密舰甲板正式投降
... ending World War II.
结束了二次世界大战
The Missouri fired the first shots of the Gulf War.
密舰于波斯湾战争率先开炮
Her powerful 16 inch guns destroyed Iraqi bunkers.
强有力的16口径摧毁国城堡
Her Tomahawk missiles rocketed deep into the heart of Baghdad.
战斧飞弹更直捣巴格达
The fastest and most powerful dreadnought ever to sail the seas...
- 堪称最快捷强大的海上战舰  - 拿去
Where's your tattoo?
你的刺青在哪？
Where I got it you don't want to see.
你可不会想知道
Now the ship will be decommissioned.
如今密舰即将退役
President Bush is paying final tribute to the ship...
布什总统做最后巡礼
... and her great history.
向密舰及其战史致敬
Did you hear the joke about Andre and Beaudreau hunting on the bayou?
听说安德和碧打猎的笑话吧
"Where're the guns Druillet? "
"枪在哪里  卓利？  "
That's about right.
学得满像的
In the end this unity of purpose...
最后凭此坚毅
These ceremonies not only remember war they celebrate peace.
仪式不仅纪念战争也庆祝和平
The President ordered the removal of all Tomahawk cruise missiles...
总统并不令撤除所有战斧飞弹  撤除法兰克泰迪
... from U.S. surface ships.
使其不再存于美国军舰
Tomorrow the ship embarks for San Francisco for her final voyage.
明天密舰将最后航行至旧金山
Her weaponry will be removed dismantled and never fired again.
舰上精密的武器将被彻除肢解  不再使用
The vessel will then take her place in naval history.
退役的密舰将安享其历史地位
We will gain the inevitable triumph so help us God.
最终的胜利将属于我们...  天助吾等
Look at the money spent on this photo opportunity.
多少纳税人的钱被花在拍照上
Ready to go sir.
准备启动  长官
Very well let's single up.
很好  拔锚吧
Aye sir. Single up all lines.
是  长官  收线
- Captain you have clear water to port. - Very well.
- 舰长  离水道已清  - 很好
Krill ain't running this ship.
圭尔又不是管事的
The old man has to okay all helicopter landings.
反正得老头答应让直升机降落
How's the captain going to authorize a surprise party for himself?
舰长会"准"他自己庆生会吗
We already stowed all the gear.
滑轮都已经收走了
What's on this helicopter?
直升机装什么？
This little sweetheart.
小甜心
- She's in the... - Yeah she's in the cake.
- 她在...没错  - 在蛋糕里
That is Miss July '89. Jordan Tate.
89年七月小姐.娇登
- We'll be ready for her. - Good. Go ahead and keep that.
- 要好好欢迎她  - 好！  那本送你
Lieutenant we don't have time to talk about this now.
波莱上尉  现在没时间说这个
No time for the security of nuclear weapons?
没时间说核子武器安全问题？
Maybe I'm not being clear.
可能是我没讲清楚
Any watches not crucial shall be secured during the party...
派对时不重要的岗哨不必留人
... including the Marine roving patrol.
军舰巡逻队也不用当班
We're operating on a skeleton crew.
现有编制已经小的可怜了
This is an order.
这是命令！
The log will show I consider this unsafe and obeyed under protest.
日志会证明我被迫执行命令
Fine.
好
Hey Cue Ball.
嗨  裘宝
Cue Ball in the house.
裘宝来了
Show me a move!
来段舞步吧
Turn up the tunes! Turn up the tunes!
大声点  音量开大
Come on show me some moves. Come on!
来嘛  跳两步嘛
Go Cue Ball!
快  裘宝
Go Cue Ball! Go Cue Ball go!
跳  裘宝跳  跳  裘宝跳！
That was cute.
真有趣...
Petty Officer Ryback?
下士雷白
- Ensign Taylor. - Sir.
- 泰勒少尉  - 长官
You don't have to "sir" me. We're casual in the galley.
不必称我长官嘛  我们在厨房都很随便的
I'd watch it. We still have a week together.
我会盯你  大家还要共渡一周
So I won't get to see you go through puberty.
我看不到你安渡思春期了
What is it?
要什么？
I have orders from the XO on the captain's birthday.
有关于舰长庆生宴的指示
We're having dinner flown in from Hawaii.
晚餐由夏威夷运来
This galley will be cleared by 1700.
厨房五点关闭
You are to report to the mess deck prior to the helo's arrival.
全体在直升机降落前到餐厅
Negative.
少来
Excuse me?
对不起？
Only I cook for the captain. You don't like that talk to him.
只有我能掌厨  你不满意的  去跟舰长说
I don't believe you get it.
你不懂是吧？
See this is a surprise party.
瞧  这是给他的惊喜
No one is going to talk to the captain about this.
不准任何人去跟他讲
You know something?
你知道吗
He don't like surprises. Neither do I.
舰长和我都不喜欢惊奇
Then I guess we'll just see what we'll see. Won't we?
那只好走着瞧了  对吧？
红头小子走罗
"I guess we'll just see what we'll see. Won't we? "
"那只好走着瞧了  是吧？  "
Krill's going to skin you alive.
圭尔一定会整你
Why is it that I'm starting to shake so bad...
怪不得我现在浑身发抖？
... and there's this deep fear in me...
一股深深的恐惧
... thinking about Mr. Krill and the horrible things he'll do to me?
想想圭尔所能整的手段
Commander Krill.
副舰长圭尔到了
Send him in.
请他进来
You wanted to see me Captain?
你要见我？
Commander Krill...
副舰长圭尔
... how'd you expect to land a helicopter without my authorization?
直升机降落怎能没有我的允许
- It was a mistake to think... - It was a mistake to try.
- 我不该以为...  - 不  你根本不该试
Your actions are grossly insubordinate.
你的行为是以下犯上
I want an explanation. Now.
马上说出理由
Admiral Bates wants to thank you for how smoothly things went.
贝兹将军感谢你及弟兄们配合
He has a surprise for your birthday.
所以给你安排了庆生会
He's flying in from Hawaii.
他会从夏威夷飞来
I see. If the admiral wants a party I guess we'll have one.
贝兹...  如果将军要开庆生会
Let's keep it simple. Off - duty personnel can attend...
那我们就开吧  但尽量简单  不值班的弟兄可以参加
... but watches remain.
但值勤的照旧
Yes sir.
是  长官
Captain...
舰长
... since he wants this to be a surprise...
既然这是给你的惊喜
... if you could stay here till we come for you...
请待在船舱等我们来接你
- I'll be engrossed in a novel. - Very good sir.
- 我会专心读小说  - 很好  长官
How's that bouillabaisse? Heads up!
鱼汤没问题吧？  当心
If I'm not mistaken...
如果我没记错的话
... every one of you has orders to report to the mess deck...
你们通通要到主甲板报到
... for the party.
因为要开舞会
Stand fast.
别动
Everyone else go! Now.
其他人上！  立刻
See you at the party.
舞会见
You know...
你知道...
... this does look delicious.
看起来满可口的
It smells like a lard omelet.
闻起来像腌肉煎蛋卷
I put up with your shit...
我忍受你的无礼
... because the captain likes your cooking.
因为舰长喜欢你的菜
But this time he won't be here to save you.
但这次他可救不了你
Is that right?
是吗？
Little flavor.
加点料
You like that?
喜不喜欢？
That's striking an officer!
你做什么？
It is not!
这是攻击上级长官
That's striking an officer!
那不是  这才是攻击上级长官
- Okay! All right! - Cuff him and throw him in the brig!
- 够了！  好了！  - 铐上他把他丢进牢房！
- In the brig! - You need the old man's signature.
- 丢进牢房  - 要有舰长签名才能关我
Good point.
说的对
Secure him in the meat locker.
把他关在冷藏室
Now! Right now!
立刻
Let's go.
走吧
Now I know why you're a cook. You hit like a faggot.
怪不得你当厨子  打起架来像同性恋
Steel.
给我
Private Nash...
纳许
- ... you came on board in Hawaii? - Yes sir.
- 你在夏威夷上舰的？  - 是  长官
Then you don't know about Ryback?
那你没听说过雷白
He is an extreme psychopath.
他精神错乱
He hates officers. He hates America.
他恨长官  恨美国
This is the captain's birthday. I don't want him ruining it.
今天是舰长生日  我可不希望他搅局
No one speaks to him or lets him out.
不准任何人和他讲话或释放他
If he tries to escape shoot him right here.
他想跑的话  你就开枪
I'm counting on you.
一切靠你了
Yes sir.
是  长官
Let's go.
我们走
Another cold day in hell.
又是个地狱般的酷寒日了
It speaks well for the Navy that we can entertain a ship at sea.
能到海上战舰劳军真不错
It's so human.
感觉很温馨
And I love that. Don't you?
我很喜欢  你呢
I just hope I don't throw up.
我只希望不要吐就好
You'll be fine.
你不会有事的
I love it. I love it!
棒极了  我会爱死
Welcome to the USS Missouri.
- 欢迎光临密苏里舰  - 谢谢
Are you OK?
没事吗？
Fantastic!
太棒了
We're looking forward to a great time.
大家都很兴奋  等着大闹一场呢
I love this business!
我爱死了这一行
My future wife.
我未来的老婆
She's landed.
她来啦
The Bunny's landed. See you.
兔女郎来了  待会见
Private!
二等兵
Doesn't it seem strange that Krill put me in here?
圭尔把我关在这不是很奇怪吗
I ain't listening to you.
我没听到你说的
Welcome aboard.
欢迎加入
Guys make a hole.
兄弟  开条路
Don't let them bother you. Been at sea too long. You okay?
别被他们吓到  海上待的太久了  你还好吧
I still feel really queasy.
还是想吐
We'll go to the wardroom where you can change.
我们到更衣室  你可以换秀服
Let the lady through!
让小姐过去
Be careful with the cake. Make sure the wires are covered.
当心蛋糕  电线可要藏好
That's the way it goes.
这才对
- Are you lost? - No no. Where do you want us?
- 你找不到路  - 不  长官  你要我们处哪儿？
- Is the band ready? - Ready.
- 乐队准备好了  - 好了
You're over here.
你  过去
Starboard side right now.
台边  靠右边  快点
You'll knock the captain off his feet. You're beautiful.
你可会把舰长迷死  你很漂亮
For motion sickness. Take two.
晕车晕船  请服两粒
Thanks. What happened to your face?
这可救了我  你脸上怎么搞的
Cut myself shaving. The cake's almost ready.
刮胡子刮到的  蛋糕马上就会装好
We have a room for you to change. You'll be safe from my men.
给你准备了一间更衣室  让你绝不会被男人骚扰
I'm going to go put on my party dress.
我也要去换秀服了  一会儿见
Don't worry. You can play this with your eyes shut.
别耽心  你闭着眼睛都跳的出来
Private!
二等兵
Let me out!
放我出去
You follow Krill's orders you'll go to the brig! Use your head!
听圭尔命令的话  你会坐牢  用大脑想想
Go get my pies out of the oven!
把派从烤箱拿出来
I must be nuts.
我一定疯了...
Very sick.
还很严重
We want to give you a great big welcome...
我们要热烈欢迎各位
... to the big beautiful Missouri lounge...
莅临壮观美丽的密舰大厅
... out here in the middle of the big beautiful Pacific Ocean.
在此优美的太平洋中
I'm Bad Billy.
我是坏蛋比利
And these are the fabulous Bail Jumpers!
他们是帅呆了的"越狱高手"
I have orders not to talk to you. Understand? Orders.
我奉命令不准和你讲话  懂吗？  是命令
You could be held accountable...
你要负责任的...
... keeping me in here like this.
把我这样关在这里
You have to think about that.
你要想清楚
Private?
二等兵？
He didn't say you can't talk to the captain.
他没说不准和舰长讲话
Go ask him if he wants me in here.
去问他要不要把我关在这
You little E - 1 prick.
你这个头号大脓包
Lieutenant this is absolutely beautiful.
上尉  弄的太好了
Old man says keep her level.
保持档次
How about an hors d'oeuvre?
来客法式开胃菜吧？
What have we here?
咱们有些什么
All right. There's the Twinkies. Where's Miss July?
来  你的夹心卷  七月小姐呢
And there she is.
她来了
Miss July 1989.
一九八九年七月号小姐
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
慢着...等等
That's not Miss July.
她不是七月小姐
My God look at him.
老天爷  看他那付德性
Commander Krill.
副舰长圭尔
Welcome to the revolution.
欢迎光临革命现场
This party'll make history. No wonder he wanted everyone here.
这场派对可要破海军纪录了  难怪他叫每个人都来
Maybe Krill isn't such an asshole after all.
圭尔其实还不算是鸟人
That's great. Go get the old man. He's been waiting on you now.
很好  去请老头下来吧  他等很久了
All right.
好的
Miss July!
七月小姐
We're going to surprise the captain now.
来吧  我们会使舰长大为惊奇
- Have a good party! - Come on dear.
- 宴会愉快  - 来
Where's the chief?
大厨呢
In the meat locker until after the party.
被关在冷冻室  直到派对结束
It's only like 40 degrees in there.
里面只有摄氏几度
He'll be fine. He's got a guard.
他不会有事的  有卫兵站岗
Krill's a maniac. Tell the captain he spit in my soup.
圭尔是疯子  去告诉舰长  他吐唾液于汤里？
You got a fire in here.
厨房着火了
Get my pies out of the oven!
把派从烤箱拿出来
These pantyhose feel good!
这内衣感觉真好
It's okay. I'm here to escort the captain to the party.
没问题  我来护送舰长进会场
Aye Commander.
好的
- Commander Krill. - Send him in.
- 副舰长圭尔来了  - 请他进来
I'm your date tonight Captain.
今晚我当你的女伴
Wait. Wait a minute!
慢着  等等
Who is the highest ranking officer here?
谁的官阶最高
Who is the highest ranking officer in this room?
现场谁的官阶最高
Stand up.
起立
Stand up and be recognized.
请起立和上台发言
Part the waves there. Get out of the man's way.
让开路  别挡路
Put a light on the man.
灯往他身上打
Now you sir are the highest ranking officer in this room?
你  长官  你官阶最高？
Yes. Operations officer. Third in command.
对  指挥官  第三顺位
It's a pleasure to meet you Commander Green.
幸会  格林指挥官
Get down!
卧倒
What's going on?
怎么回事
The party's just beginning.
舞会刚开始
Captain!
舰长
Good shot.
好枪法
Lay down! Hands up!
蹲下  双手举起了
Heads down!
头低下
What are you looking at? On the floor!
你看什么？  卧在地板上
Put your head down.
头放低
You want to be good now?
学乖了吧
What is this a joke?
这是开玩笑吗？
No joke!
不是
I hear gunfire. What's going on?
有枪声  怎么回事
料理他
It's done.
好了
Four minutes ahead of schedule.
超前四分钟  我好棒
快走  走啊
Mother Goose the quails are in the nest.
老母鹅  小鹅都进窝了
It's just the music.
是音乐
You got shit for brains. That's gunfire. Call the bridge.
你没脑袋  快呼叫舰桥
I don't know who you're talking to. No one's listening.
我不知道你在跟谁讲话  没人在听
I ain't asking you to listen to me.
我不是叫你听我的
Call the captain. Listen to him.
快呼叫舰长
快走...走啊
Seal it!
封死
走...移动脚
走  走啊  移动脚
快走
往前走  往前走...
Eyes on the man in front of you!
看好前排的那个
Goddamn it that's the last time I'll tell you!
妈的！  这是我最后一次警告你
Let this be a learning experience.
学着点
If you resist we will kill you and the man next to you.
反抗的话就杀你和前后左右
Now move out of here in an orderly fashion.
现在  依次离开这里
Now!
立刻
怎么了？
士官！  双手举起
Turn around. Hands on your head.
转身  手放头上
Where is it?
在哪里呢
Here it is.
找到了
Listen to the shit I've had to put up with.
听听这段说我的烂话
"Commander Krill has become increasingly hostile to the crew...
数周来圭尔待人更形恶劣
... possibly due to anger over reviews of his performance.
可能兴我上次对其的评鉴有关
I recommend psychological evaluation before his next assignment."
建议于其调动前做心理测验
Do I look like I need a psychological evaluation?
我看起来需要心理测验吗
Not at all.
一点也不
I got to change.
我要换衣服了
Behind your head.
手放在头后
Up against the wall.
举起来靠墙
XO on the bridge.
值星官已到舰桥了
Listen up.
听着
Hands on your head and move to the counter right now.
手放头上  立刻移向前台前
Your destination is the fo'c's'le. Cooperate and you won't be harmed.
你们的目标是前甲板舱  只要合作就不会有事
Change of watch.
换岗  屁股挪过来！  快点
You've done a good job but you're relieved of duty.
你们干的很好  今天不必值勤  快点  你聋了  出去
Get your hand off that console.
手别碰控制盘  全部的人  出去
You're a cheeky bastard. Move out!
不要脸的小混混  出去！
My God! Bunch of wussies.
我的天  娘儿们
The disk Mr. Pitt.
磁碟片  皮特先生
Guard it with your life.
看好
Of course.
一定
Bring up the layout if you will.
船舱图带过来
- We've overridden their systems. - We control crypto CIC...
- 已经停摆了他们系统  - 也掌握了密码和作战中心
... engine rooms boiler rooms bridge and all open decks.
引擎室  机房  舰桥及各甲板
We've welded shut the hatches.
通道的门也都封死了
A few loose sailors may be berthing...
裘宝少数几个水手还在晃荡
... or they're caught in nonessential areas and can go nowhere.
反正不会阻止我们的计划
- The rest are in the fo'c's'le. - Excellent.
- 其他的都在前甲板舱  - 好极了
Reactivate the weapons systems Mr. Pitt.
重新启动武器系统  皮特
Mr. Daumer...
多玛先生...
... you may deploy the welding crews and chop up broadway.
焊接队可以在通道作业了
Commander Krill you're hereby promoted to captain.
副舰长圭尔  现在你是舰长了
Congratulations. The ship is yours.
恭喜  船是你的了
The ship is mine.
船是我的
Thank you Billy. All right!
谢谢  好棒
Can we get something to eat in here?!
有没有吃的
Get some food!
拿点吃的来
Krill warned me you were tricky.
圭尔说你很狡猾
I'm not tricky I'm just freezing. Something's going on here.
我不是狡猾  是快冻僵了  事有问题
Call the bridge. No one'll yell at you.
呼叫舰桥  他们不会骂你的
It's just your job. Check right away.
你在尽责而已  快查
All right. All right I'll check.
好吧  我查一下
That's all.
别的少来
Do that. And be careful.
快查  小心点
'Tis a rare thing.
满不赖的嘛
This is good. It'll work.
很好  会有帮助
Got a call from Private Nash on guard duty in the kitchen.
纳许在呼叫  说他在厨房值勤
Pitt pull it up.
皮特  找出厨房所在位置
That's an unsecured area. They can access the whole ship.
还没清查过...从那可通全舰
Ryback. A cook. A pain - in - the - ass cook.
雷白  厨子  难缠的要死
Give me that.
电话给我
Private Nash.
二等兵纳许  长官！
I'm glad you checked in. I've been with the captain.
我很高兴你呼叫了  我和舰长在一起
Keep Ryback under control and don't open the door.
看好雷白  千万别开门
Tell him you're sending relief.
说你派人去换班
Tell him you are sending somebody to relieve him.
Stand your station fast. I'm sending someone to relieve you.
好好站岗  我派人去换班
Is everything okay? We heard what sounded like gunshots.
没事吧？  我们好像听到枪声
Gunshots? Oh that.
枪声？  噢  那个啊...
Those are party poppers. Firecrackers.
是派对爆竹  烟火...
Part of the party.
生日派对的部分活动
Stand firm until you're relieved.
好好站岗
- Yes sir. - Over and out.
- 是  长官  - 完毕
Anything else you didn't tell us?
还有你没讲的？  什么
Any further memory lapses or oversights perhaps?
一时间忘记的...
No other memory lapses or oversights perhaps.
之类的
There's two men. One's locked up. I'll take care of it.
两个人  一个关起来了  我会处理他
We'll handle it. Secure the galley. Send Cates and Ziggs.
我们来弄  扫荡厨房  派凯斯和齐格下去
This Marine's armed.
卫兵有武器
We need more. I'll go.
人手要多  我去
Don't worry. They're professionals.
放心  他们有专业水准
They can handle twenty Marines...
能摆平二十个海军...
... and 100 cooks.
和一百个厨子
You're wrong Ryback. You're wrong.
你错了  雷白  你错了
- They were party poppers. - You got shit for brains.
- 根本是派对爆竹  - 你没脑子
I know they brainwashed you but you have to question authority.
在新兵训练营给洗脑了  你一定要对上级质疑
Trust me boy.
相信我  小老弟
That's gunfire. Free me and I'll take care of it.
那是枪声  放我出去我来解决
I'll be relieved in a few minutes so just shut up and sit tight.
几分钟内我就交班了  你最好给我闭嘴坐好
Something's going on. Use your head this time.
一定是出事了  这次用用你的脑子
Do what you got to do. Let me out.
做你该做的  放我出去
Or when I'm out I'll shoot you myself.
不然等我出来了  一定宰你
Commander Krill?
副舰长圭尔
Is that you?
是你吗？
Get your hands on your head. Turn around.
手放头上...头上  转过身来
Get down on your knees.
跪下
Cross your ankles.
两脚交叉
Where's the cook?
厨子呢？
In the reefer.
冰库里
Which one?
哪一座？
Son of a bitch!
他妈的！
凯斯
We've got an F - 18.
发现一架战斗机F  - 18
They sent an F - 18 to look for the chopper.
多玛  他们派F  - 18来找直升机
Heading 315 miles speed 430 approximately 8000.
行驶315英里  时速四百英里  标高约八千英尺
207 61 miles now.
207号  只剩六十一英里
430. 5000 now into descent.
标高五千  开始下降
We're going down now.
下降
Looks like one helo on deck.
似乎有架直升机在甲板上
零方位
Going in for a closer look.
飞近一看
31 to Missouri over.
31呼叫密苏里
Goodbye!
再会了
Are you tracking me?
你在侦测我？
Negative.
不是
He's locked me up! Mayday.
他锁定我了！  救命！
Welcome to the revolution.
欢迎加入革命阵容
Better call the office.
连络海军危机处理中心  好主意
You're in deep kimchi buddy.
你的麻烦大了
Better have it all in one sock for this one.
最好一次解决掉
Claims he was a company man who worked for you.
自称以前在中情局是你手下
What's his name?
叫什么
William Strannix.
威廉  史传尼
Jesus Christ!
我的天哪！
Not good.
不妙
不妙.
Mr. Breaker...
贝克先生
... you better be candid with us here tonight.
今晚你最好坦白一点
We need answers and we need them now.
我们立刻需要知道答案
Gentlemen if any ships or aircraft approach within 100 miles...
听好  诸位  如有飞机军艇迫近一百英里内
... we will kill the crew and retaliate using the ship's arsenal.
我们就枪杀船员  以示报复
Bill this is Tom. What's going on?
比尔  我是汤姆  怎么回事
I have 32 Tomahawks under my thumb...
汤姆  有32枚战斧飞弹在我手中
... and all you can do is alert the media.
你唯一能做的就是知会新闻界
You don't have the launch codes.
你没有发射密码
Let me guess.
让我猜猜...
弹指令密码
"5- 6- 6- 0- 4- 9- 9- 7- 8- 0? "
五  - 六  - 六  - 零  - 四  - 九  - 九  - 七  - 八  - 零？
This is insane.
你疯了
Be careful with that word Tom.
小心你的用词遣字  汤姆
This is Admiral Bates speaking. Tell us why you're doing this.
史传尼先生  我是贝兹上将  为什么你要这么做呢
Hi Admiral!
嗨  将军！
Six months ago Tom Breaker canceled Operation Cleopatra.
半年前汤姆取消艳后行动
Shortly thereafter two young men from Langley tried to cancel me.
之后  很短时间内  两个总部派来的人又要干掉我
Didn't you receive each man's forefinger in the mail?
你没收到他们的食指吗？
汤姆？
Yes.
收到了
Did you expect us to wait for you to try again?
你以为我们会坐以待毙
I know things are a little...
我知道事情现在对你来说...
... chaotic for you right now. - Chaotic!
- 有点混乱  - 混乱！
Wake up!
你醒醒！  汤姆
You and I know that chaos and bedlam are consuming the entire world.
你和我都知道  混乱和骚动已然盘据整个世界
UV rays are only the beginning. We have an inch of topsoil left.
大气层的被破坏只是开始  我们所有的土地只剩一英寸厚
Topsoil?
土地表层
Sexually transmitted diseases depletion of the gene pool.
性病  森林滥砍  基因乱配
It adds up to oblivion.
一切都将为人遗忘
Governments will fall. Anarchy will reign.
政府会垮台  无政府统治
It's a brave new world.
美丽新世界
What are you planning to do?
你打算怎么做
Do you realize that whatever I do is inevitable? Can we agree on that?
不管我做什么都是势在必行  你同意吧
Not necessarily.
未必
There you go.
又来了
You can't argue with me or negotiate or attempt a ploy.
不要跟我争论  商议或使诈
You have to reconsider your philosophy.
要反省一下你的策略
All right I'm sorry. Whatever you decide to do is inevitable.
好吧  抱歉  你做的都是势在必行的
Look at my life.
拿我的一条命来说...
The life you tried to take. There was Annapolis Vietnam so on.
你们这些人就想要取  我进过军校  打过越战
I missed the 60s and I believe if I had been there...
我错过了六十年  我相信如果我能在美国贡献
... to contribute everything would've been fine.
所有事会因此改观
Bill if this is about reliving the 60s you can forget it.
如果只为了要过60年代干瘾  我劝你还是算了
The movement is dead.
群众运动早死了
Hence the name.
所以才被叫做"运动"
It moves a certain distance then it stops.
它只移动了一下就停了
Revolution gets its name by always coming back around in your face.
革命则会永远卷土重来
You tried to kill me you son of a bitch.
你还想要杀我...臭婊子
So welcome to the revolution.
欢迎加入革命阵容
There's more to follow. I'll stay in touch.
稍后请继续  保持连络
He's flipped.
他精神有病
He's completely flipped.
完全疯了
I want a list of everything on that ship.
- 我要一份密舰配备清单  - 是  长官
General here's what we know.
将军  给你报告
The threat is verifiable. It is real. I repeat it is real.
恐吓经查证属实  那是真的  我再重覆  是真的
Shit! You son of a bitch.
见鬼  见鬼
Think they believe you?
他们相信你？
They believe I'm crazy paranoid or something.
不知道  他们说我发疯  失常
I have a harpoon locked on.
鱼叉飞弹已经锁定
Fire when ready.
准备好就发射
Pipe down men! Pipe down.
安静  搞什么
Missile away.
飞弹升空
Oh boy.
好家伙
Oh boy oh boy.
好家伙  好家伙
Bang! You're dead.
碰...！  你死定了
- He's taken out satellite relay. - What doesn't he want us to see?
- 他已破坏卫星中继站  - 不让我们探知密舰所在位置
He wants to blind us.
要让我们摸不透
It's illogical. We can follow his movement from Pearl.
不合逻辑反正我们能从  珍珠港雷达得知密舰动向
You can vector an AWACS.
可使用警控系统去追踪
- Or send E - 2C from Nimitz. - Do it.
- 或从尼米兹舰  - 派遣E2C侦察机
Wake up the President.
去做  叫醒总统
Bring it in.
拿焊枪来
Keep it coming in.
来了
Cut it fast. Time is money on this deal.
快烧  他火了  时间就是金钱
- They better be competent. - Get your ass up there!
- 他们最好能办事  - 快上去！
Watch your heads.
小心头
Glad I sent you the blueprints.
幸好我给你舰图了  说吧
I have 4 sections this way 7 sections this way.
这边分四路  那边分七路
I'll have it cut and up in an hour.
一个小时内会好
焊枪拿来
Time is money on this job!
时间就是金钱
Time is money.
时间...就是金钱
This will cut them to the bone. Right to the bone.
这可会把他们打的稀烂  打得稀烂
What's that noise?
那是什么声音？
That's my beloved crew.
我亲爱的船员
Keep trying. Keep pounding. Someone will hear us.
再试试  拼命敲  总有人会听到我们
Shut the music off.
把音乐关掉
What the hell's going on?
到底怎么回事？
What happened to them?
人呢？
- Who are you and why are you here? - My name is Jordan Tate.
- 你是谁？  怎么在这里？  - 我叫娇登  台特
I'm Miss July '89.
一九八九年七月小姐
I was hired to jump out of the cake...
他们雇我来从蛋糕里跳出来
... but I got airsick on the way here and so...
但是飞来的时候我晕机
... this guy gave me these pills.
有一个人拿药给我吃
- I guess I fell asleep. - What kind of bullshit is this!
- 我就睡着了  - 你说的是满篇鬼话
I am an actress okay?
我是个演员
I did a Hunter episode and a Wet 'n Wild video.
拍过一集"猎杀者"  和"又湿又野"录影带
My agent said I was going to jump out of the cake.
经纪人说我只要跳出蛋糕就好
How many on the chopper?
直升机上有几个人
I don't know.
不晓得
It was full. There was a band and caterers.
不过很满  有乐队和厨师
Where's the crew?
机员呢？
I don't know. I didn't see anything.
不知道  我什么也没看到
You didn't see or hear anything and don't remember anything?
你没看到没听到也不记得了
I've done stupid things in my life...
我这一生是做过不少傻事
... but believe me I don't know anything.
但是  我真的不知道
All right I believe you.
好  我相信你
So who are you? Are you a special forces guy or something?
你呢？  你是什么特种部队吧
I'm just a cook.
我只是个厨子
A cook?
厨子？
Just a lowly lowly cook.
只是个微不足道的小厨子
My God we're going to die.
老天！  我们死定了
The ship contains 40 000 rounds of 20mm CWIZ.
舰上配有四万枚追踪飞弹
Over 1000 16- inch projectiles.
超过一千枚的十六英寸飞弹
We believe there's 15 harpoon cruise missiles still aboard...
相信该舰另有十五枚鱼叉飞弹
... and 32 Tomahawks.
及三十二枚战斧
What kind of Tomahawks?
哪一种战斧
It's all right. It's okay.
没关系  你可以说
Eight of them are specials.
八枚特种级
Nuclear - tipped. 220 kilotons each.
核子弹头  每枚含二十二万吨炸药
Mr. Breaker would you explain how this nut could hold a top position...
贝克先生  这样的疯子怎能任职
... in an intelligence agency?
在中情局
Would you answer that?
你能回答吗？
High - level covert operatives like Strannix are under great stress.
高级探员像史传尼的压力很大
They're creative thinkers who by their very nature...
他们先天都很有创造力
Tom trains everyone in the CIA who's crazy.
汤姆在中情局专门训练疯子
All we want to know is how he got our battleship.
我们想知道的是...  他怎么弄到战舰的
That's his specialty.
那是他的特长
North Korea was refitting a sub to fire antiship missiles...
最近北韩重装一艘潜艇  以发射反舰飞弹
... so we sent Strannix in.
所以我们叫史传尼去
You've been financing this maniac's private army?
你在支持这个疯狂计划
You didn't think it might be a problem?
也不想想可能会出事
Once we realized we'd lost positive control...
我们发现总统不认可此计划后
... we tried to neutralize him. We missed.
立刻要他停止  却失败了
Excuse me.
恕我插嘴...
This North Korean sub...
这艘北韩潜艇
How do you know he sunk it?
你怎么知道他把它炸沉了
Oh we're positive he sunk it.
噢  我们肯定是他
Positive.
肯定
Roadrunner to Tweety Bird. Do you read me? Come in.
"跑路者"叫"小鸣鸟"  听到我了吗？  请回答
Tweety Bird to Roadrunner. We're nearby.
"小鸣鸟"叫"跑路者"  我们很近
- How's it going? - Sub's up.
- 进行的如何  - 潜艇浮出海了
- It's all rock and roll to me. - Any sign of Wile E. Coyote?
- 一切照进度  - 有没有看到惠利小子？
No. Meet at the birdcage. Roadrunner out.
没有  照计划于鸟笼见  "跑路者"通话完毕
You're the Roadrunner?
你是跑路者？
Never been caught.
从没被抓过
Problem. Cates and Ziggs are missing.
出状况了  凯斯  齐格失踪
I radioed them repeatedly. No response.
一直呼叫他们  却没回答
- The last location? - The galley.
- 最后所在位置  - 厨房
I told you to send more men. I told you.
告诉你要多派点人  告诉你
Please don't leave me here alone.
不要留我一个人在这儿
Believe me this is the safest place you can be. Understand?
相信我  这里最安全  懂吗？
Let me out of here!
放我出去！
Let me out!
Do you understand what'll happen if anybody hears you?
知道有人听到你叫会怎样吗？
They'll try to kill us.
会把我们杀了
Now be quiet.
安静点
I hate being alone.
我最怕一个人
Do you hate being dead?
怕不怕死？
Check it
检查一下
Clear!
检查完毕
Put those on.
换上这些
You're coming with me you got to be invisible.
你跟我来  但是要掩护好
If you're by a hatch and see the enemy you become the hatch.
如果碰到敌人时你正在舱口
I'm giving you this rifle with a selector switch on it.
那就站着扮成舱口  给你这把有选择开关的来福枪
One is fully automatic one is semiautomatic.
一边是全自动  一边是半自动
The definition of semiautomatic is when you depress the trigger...
半自动的定义是说  当你扣下扳机
... one round will go off.
就发射一枚子弹
That's what I want to give you. Spend one round at a time.
这就是我要给你的  一次射一发  好吗？
Turn on the lights.
开灯
Check the breaker box. It's happened before.
检查线路板  以前也这样过
Man who did this is a professional.
行家干的
- Who is he and why is he on my ship? - Your ship?
- 是谁？  怎么会在我的船上？  - 你的船？
You wouldn't be on this battleship if not for me.
要不是我你根本不可能在船上
He's a cook plain and simple.
他是厨子  就这样
- A cook didn't do this. - He came with the captain.
- 厨子做不出来的  - 他和舰长一起来
I know his routine front and back. He's good with cooking knives.
他的底细我摸的很熟  他专长耍菜刀
Cooking knives!
这不是菜刀
He got lucky.
他运气好
In my professional opinion he is a military reject...
据我看  是军队不要他
... in command of a galley.
所以才来管厨房
Get down!
趴下
- What was that? - A bomb jackass.
- 是什么啊？  - 炸弹  笨蛋
He used the microwave as a detonator.
他用微波炉当雷管
Secure everything between here and the CIC.
清查这里和作战指挥中心之间
You see anything radio at once for backup. Understand?
一看到可疑情况就呼叫找帮手  懂吗
Put these fires out!
快灭火
I'd like to see the personnel file on this "simple cook."
我要瞧瞧这个大厨师的档案  舰长先生
Put out these goddamn fires!
灭他妈的火啊
SEAL Team 5 will launch from Nimitz aboard a CH - 53 Echo...
尼米兹舰  乘坐CH  - 55乘直升机出发
... with an Apache gunship in support.
另有阿帕契战斗直升机护航
At the objective area the Apache will take out the ship's radar...
在目标区内阿帕契会摧毁雷达
... and her electronic warfare systems.
及电子作战系统
Then SEAL Team 5 will board and retake the ship.
然后第五队上船收复失舰
And the odds of success?
成功的机率呢？
If it's a lunatic who only partly controls the ship...
如果那个疯子只有部分控制...
... the odds are good.
机率便很大
But if he's ready for us...
但  如果他准备充分
... if he's prepared to repel boarders...
如果他会击退登舰者...
... the odds are not good.
机率便不大
Bear in mind the operators from SEAL Team 5 are the best there are.
话又说回来  第五队都是精锐
This is our only hope of saving the crew and retaking the ship.
是我们唯一拯救舰员  收复失舰的机会
Let me make one thing absolutely clear:
让我说明一件事
If the SEAL team fails...
如果特种部队失败
... we will have no alternative but to launch an air strike...
我们就只有发动空中攻击
... and destroy the Missouri.
摧毁密舰
You know what that means.
你们都明白此举严重性
We'll get her back for you.
我们会取回失舰
Make it happen. Make it happen.
做给我看
22... 12... perfect.
22度  12度  太棒了
It's 44 feet from the weather deck to the missile canisters.
从甲板到飞弹有44英里
It'll take a half hour to assemble that section of the crane.
三十分钟装设该处的起重机
Ryback's file was in the captain's private cabinet.
雷白的档案  不在人事档案室  在舰长保险柜里
Ryback is an ex - SEAL.
他以前是三栖特种部队
The goddamn cook's a SEAL?
厨子是特种部队？
Shut up and listen. "Expert in martial arts...
你闭嘴听好  "国术专家"  精通
... explosives weapons tactics.
爆破  武器  战略
Silver Star. Navy Cross. Purple Heart with cluster.
获银星奖  海军十字奖  紫心勋章加饰徽
Security revoked after Panama." So he could only rate as a yeoman...
巴拿马事件后特许证撤消  所以他不能有官阶
... or a cook. How little did I know.
除了  小兵或厨子  我够孤陋寡闻了
We lost two men in the engine room.
引擎室又损失两名部下
You were told to review every crew member's file.
告诉过你要每个船员档案
I know but I didn't have access to the captain's files!
我知  但拿不到舰长私有档案
- I'll get this fucker myself. - Oh no calm down.
- 我来亲自收拾这家伙  - 安静点...
- Want to get killed? - Are you an idiot?
- 你想被杀吗？  - 你是笨蛋啊？
- You're calling me an idiot? - Yes I am.
- 你叫我笨蛋  - 正是
Calm down. Get me three roving patrols. Keep him below the weather deck.
镇静一点  给我三组巡逻队  把他卡在甲板下
- Move out! - Stay on schedule!
- 快去！  - 照进度行事
To the bridge!
我们去舰桥
I'm the girl. Why do I have to carry everything?
我是女孩  为什么都要我拿
- I support women's lib don't you? - When it's in my favor.
- 我支持妇女解放  你难道不  - 对我有好处时才支持
- Hear this all personnel. - Move ahead.
- 听好  全体舰员  - 往前走
Beware of booby traps.
"小心陷阱炸弹"
Do not pursue hostile parties into unsecured areas.
不要在没巡逻队区内接近敌人
Report to Daumer individually at 5- minute intervals and switch...
个别于休息时向多玛报告
... to the alternate frequency.
并改换无线电频率
Now.
立即执行
Goddamn SEAL.
他妈的特种部队
I'll carry everything...
我来拿东西
... if you kill whoever we run into.
你来杀敌人
I have a rule about killing people.
我有我杀人的原则
Actually I have two rules. One:
事实上  我有两个原则  第一
I don't date musicians. And two I don't kill people.
不和搞音乐的约会  第二  我不杀人
I'm thrilled to death to hear that.
听到这个我可高兴死了
But it leaves a lot of open territory. Get up the ladder.
表示确实有许多事你会去做  爬上梯子
- Let's go. - God!
- 走啊  - 天啦
I think you've got the wrong partner.
你找错拍档了
Now wait here.
等着
Sit down there.
坐在那儿
I'll be back in a minute.
我马上回来
What's that?
那是什么？
What is that?
This is a SEAL magnaphone.
特种部队连线电话
It's an MX 20- 20. It's a secure satellite uplink.
MX20- 20  防窃听卫星电话
Like a car phone.
就像汽车电话一样
Yeah. Something like that.
对  像那样
Excuse me this is hot.
抱歉  上将  这是新消息
You know Casey Ryback?
你认识凯兹  雷白
Chief Ryback?
雷白队长
He's top hand in the Teams. Wish we had him here.
他是顶尖的  他在就好了
He's calling on a SEAL magnaphone from the ship.
他从船上打卫星电话来
What?
什么？
Listen. Everyone listen up.
听好  诸位
Affirmative.
正确
Can you estimate the size of the force?
能估计的出对方兵力吗？
I'd say about 30.
大约三十人
We'll connect you to Captain Garza.
我们帮你接葛兹上校
Stand by.
请稍候
What if he's working for them?
万一他替对方工作呢？
- I guarantee Ryback's a good guy. - Wait a minute.
- 我来担保雷白  他是好人  - 等等
We won't take the chance. Don't tell him our plan.
我们不该冒险  别把计划告诉他
- Chief Ryback Captain Garza. - Glad you're there.
- 大厨雷白  我是葛兹上校  - 很高兴你也在
What we want you to do is just feed us on - site intel.
现在要你做的是提供现场情报
This man may be crazy but he's a professional.
他虽然很疯狂  但他很专业
They're manufacturing a railing system to offload the Tomahawks.
他们装配栏杆要来拆战斧飞弹
Believe it or not the X O's with them.
副舰长也跟他们一伙
Commander Krill's involved?
副舰长圭尔也涉及此事？
Admiral...
将军
... that means they control the ship.
他们占领了军舰
Holy God.
我的天
Chief Ryback this is Admiral Bates speaking.
大厨雷白  我是贝兹上将
Coordinate your efforts with us. I want you to keep cool...
尽量配合我们  明白吧？  保持镇静
... and wait for the strike team. Do you understand?
等待突击队  懂吗？
I'll go before they pick up the signal.
他们发现前我最好关机
- Call us in half an hour. - Roger that.
- 三十分钟内再通话  - 知道了
You're not a cook.
你不是厨子
Yeah well...
这个嘛
... I also cook.
我也会做菜
Get your stuff.
拿好东西
He had an extremely distinguished career until Panama...
他在巴拿马事件前一帆风顺
... when most of his team died due to poor intelligence.
该役中由于情报不足队员全死
Ryback's a warrior. The best there is.
他是斗士  最好的那种
When he got back from Panama he punched his officer in charge.
巴拿马回来后他把上司打一顿
Adams took him on as a cook so he could finish his 20.
亚当带他上船让他把兵役服完
Hold it. Just hold it.
慢着
What if this toad Zwieback or whatever his name is is right...
要是"小白"或什么的讲实话
... and the missiles are offloaded before the SEAL team gets there?
飞弹真的在突击队到前被拆呢
There is no way for Mr. Strannix to get past us.
史传尼不可能办的到
We have AWAC surveillance and SOSUS in Honolulu...
我们有空中警控装置  及檀香山的安全防卫系统
... tracking every ship and sub at sea.
能侦测海上每艘舰艇
They leave the Missouri they're ours.
一旦飞弹离舰  马上抓得到
How do we know that Honolulu isn't his next target?
怎么知道檀香山不是下个目标
Tell me that.
你来告诉我
上来帮他一下
快滚上来
Take a look at this.
看看这个
- Know what all those lights are for? - I've been trained.
- 这些小红灯是做什么的？  - 受过训
You can fly that helicopter?
你会驾直升机？  对
Then we can get out of here right?
那我们就能逃走了？  不
Here's the MP5K.
这枝是MP  - 5K
When the dot's on target what you see is what you get.
红灯瞄准以后  一定射中
- I told you I don't like guns. - I know. Neither do I.
- 告诉过你我不喜欢枪  - 我知道  我也不喜欢
Now get back under there.
现在回原位去
These things are going to sell like hot cakes!
这些飞弹可卖的快了
Absolutely.
一定的
What'll you do with the $200 million?
二亿美金你要怎么花？
Buy the Presidency.
买个总统当一当
溶剂
Someone's moving. Right there!
有人影  那里！
He's on the flight deck! Go! Go!
他在起降甲板区
在那里？  油箱
Come out of there!
出来
Where are you taking me? I don't know anything!
你要带我去哪儿？  我不知道任何事
Let go of me!
让我走  放开我
Get your hands off me!
别碰我  马上放我走
Now!
放手  该死
Move!
走
他在那边
Move!
退后
Stand fast! Do not pursue that man!
别靠近  别追那个人
- Secure missile battery three now! - Man that hatch!
- 检查第三号飞弹电池  立刻  - 站好岗哨
This guy's a pain in the ass!
这家伙难缠
We got to do something about him.
得想办法对付他
I know what to do.
我知道怎么做
I do.
真的
This insanity is so logical.
计划虽疯狂却也合理
There's a sprinkler system where they're being held.
关船员的地方有消防系统
Mr. Pitt?
皮特先生
The fo'c's'le.
水手舱
Hit a button it starts to flood.
按一下钮就开始进水
In a short time they'll all drown.
马上  他们就被淹死
Ryback'll kill himself to save them.
雷白一定会来救他们
You're a maniac.
你真是头号疯子
Drowning your own crew.
淹死自己的船员
They never liked me anyway.
他们反正也不喜欢我
Bet they fucking love you now.
打赌现在一定爱死你
You see this? These are cut everywhere.
看到没有？  到处都有焊接痕迹
What is it?
那是什么？
They're for a railing system to offload the missiles onto a ship or sub...
是拆除飞弹的铁栏杆系统
... they'll rendezvous with.
好把飞弹移往别舰或潜水艇
What's that?
什么声音啊？
Morse code.
摩斯密码
What're they saying?
说什么？
"Get me the fuck out of here."
"他妈的放我出去"
- What's that? - Get away from the hatch!
- 那是什么声音？  - 别靠近舱门  又玩什么把戏
是雷白
Guard the door. Shoot anyone who comes through.
看好门  人来就开枪
You okay?
你还好吧
你呢
Is this all of you?
只有你们  是的
Six of us got trapped. What's happening?
我们六个被困  发生了什么事
We got a problem. Who's this?
出问题了  他是哪位？
Calaway Gunner's mate 2nd class '44 '46.
卡荣威  副炮手  二等兵
This is Jordan. She's a casualty of the situation I'll brief you on.
她是娇登  受害人  我马上会报告状况
Nice to see you. You too Case.
幸会  见到你真好
Granger you take this.
贺杰  你拿这个
Get your tools. We've got work to do.
拿好工具  要干活了
We're jumping into a shit storm here.
马上要往暴风圈中跳了
Must've been a power surge.
一定是电流关系  对
That's the last one.
最后一个了
This should disable their weapons systems within a half hour.
武器系统会在半小时内停摆
Mr. Ryback may I have your attention please?
雷白先生请注意好吗？
This is Captain Krill speaking.
我是圭尔舰长
I'd like you to look at the monitors...
希望你看看电视荧幕
... where you are at this point in time.
你在的地方就有
Are you watching?
你在看吗？
I prepared a special show for you.
为你特别准备了一场戏
Here it goes.
开始啦
I want you to know there are no hard feelings.
讲明白我们绝无恶意
I have no grudge against you...
我也不恨你
... or the rest of the crew.
或其他船员
You did your best.
你尽了全力
Discipline is right out the window here.
所有训练都被抛到脑后
Turn it off.
关掉,
We got to save them.
我们一定要救他们
They'll have a trap.
明知有陷阱
But they're expecting me not all of us.
但他们要抓的是我  不是你们
All of what? I do laundry.
什么我们？  我只管洗衣服啊
I ironed during the Gulf War. I ain't cut out for this.
波湾战争时我也只管烫衣服  我可不是英雄
You're in the Navy remember?
你是海军  记得吗？
"It's not a job it's an adventure."
这不是职务  是探险
To hell with that. I'm on the college program.
管它是什么！  我还是军校生呢
I'm in.
我去！  走！
All right I'll stay and watch Miss July.
好吧  我留下来照顾七月小姐
- Get the lights out in broadway. - I'm going.
- 通道的灯能不能弄灭  - 我也去
Okay but the emergency lights will kick on soon.
可以  但紧急灯马上又会亮
All right what the hell. How does this work?
管它的！  这枪怎么用？
Go!
快！
Take cover! Get down!
找掩护！  卧倒！  伏下
Turn it!
关掉！
Turn the water off!
切水源
They're going to get us out!
他们来救我们了
Pull him out of there! Pull him out!
拉他！  拉他走  帮我！  杰克
Come on buddy!
快啊
Breathe!
吸气！
Listen to him!
照他说的做！
Hang in there!
撑下去！  妈的
一小时后卸下飞弹
Listen he freed a few men and I think...
注意  他救出几名水手
... they went into the fo'c's'le but we got them pinned down.
他们跑到前舱去了  但我们仍能完全掌握
Kill them if you can't contain them.
他们乱动的话就杀
It worked. They're trapped.
你的计划成功了  他们被困了
- Good. - Drop the anchor!
- 好  - 下锚
This is where it's going to happen.
会怎样呢？  退后
- Who the hell's this? - Who the hell's this?
- 哈罗！  你是谁？  - 你又是谁？
This is Admiral Bates. I'm trying to get ahold of Ryback.
贝兹上将  我找雷白
He's in a gunfight. I'll have to take a message.
他在吗？  他正在火拼  我可以替你留话
What's going on there?
你们在搞什么？
Hold on. Here.
请稍候  来
Yes sir.
是  长官
Chief Ryback this is Admiral Bates.
大厨雷白  我是贝兹上将
I see that you completely disobeyed my orders. Correct?
显然你完全违背了的的命令
Sorry. You can court - martial me if I live.
抱歉  长官  如还有命  你可以军法审判我
I see.
我懂了
Listen to me carefully.
仔细听好
SEAL Team 5 is en route. You understand?
- 特种第五队已经出发  懂吗？  - 是  长官
Nimitz air group is our backup. Understand?
- 空降部队会支援我们  懂吗？  - 是  长官
Now since your ass is on the line I authorize you...
既然要负全责的是你
... to do whatever you can to aid the arrival of the SEALs.
我给你充份授权  去协助特种部队的登舰
Because if I goddamn can't control you...
因为我既然不能让你听命
... I might as well support you. Correct?
那不如支持你  对吧？
Affirmative.
正确
Good luck there sailor. I'm out.
祝你好运  水手  我要挂断了
They got a lot of trouble on that ship.
那艇上的麻烦还真不小
Here I go.
我走啦
I'm not staying here.
我可不在这干等了
Where're you going? Get back here.
你去哪里？  快回来！  她在你后面跟来了
- What're you doing? - The safest place is behind you.
- 你做什么？  - 最安全的地方在你背后
Hug the wall. Get out of the middle!
靠墙站  不要走在通道中间
Miss July come back here!
七月小姐  快回来！
雷白
杀了他  卡洛斯
卡洛斯
TAG leader this is Cobra escort. We have you in our sights.
空战队长  这是眼镜蛇  我们看见你们了
You should see us on your portside now.
我们正在你的左舷
Francois put the money in the Zurich bank now or nothing'll happen.
法兰克  今天就把钱存进瑞士银行  干！  史传尼
Sell what we got in MacGregor Aircraft.
把麦格飞机的股票都卖掉
It'll go to shit when they find out about this.
消息一见报它可就一文不值了
Two choppers trying to sneak in under our radar.
两架直升机低飞进来
Strike team.
突击队
We drive a hard bargain for hard value.
我们要价高  但一分钱一分货
You give me any more trouble I'll call Mohammed. Understand?
听好  我的朋友  再找麻烦我就打给穆罕默德了  明白吗？
Strike team is in range and locked on.
突击队进入射程并被锁定
Kill them.
宰了他们
Not you Francois. I'll put my accountant on the line...
不不  法兰克  不是指你！  我叫会计师来跟你讲
... with my account number. Talk to that frog.
他会给你银行帐户  这里！
Something's wrong.
出问题了
We've got a big problem here. Switch to auxiliary!
出大问题了  完蛋  快换辅助系统
Nothing.
没用
Shit I lost the phalanx. We're sitting ducks.
糟糕  自动雷达反击不灵了  简直是坐以待毙
Get me secure to the sub.
给我接通潜水艇了
Sub's up.
对方收到了
Coyote this is Roadrunner. Come in.
"土狼"  这是"跑路者"  请回答
Here come the good guys.
救星来了
210号班机
One minute!
一分钟
一分钟！
The fantail's fouled up! We're going in on the bow.
船尾全毁了  我们降落船首
What the hell was that?!
那是什么
It's confirmed. We lost them all.
消息被证实  全军覆没
We have no choice now...
现在别无选择了
... but full air assault from the Nimitz.
只有靠尼米兹舰的空中攻击了
Mr. Trenton would you please?
传顿先生  劳驾打个电话吧
We need more hands on deck to help tie this sub up.
需要更多人手到甲板拆除飞弹
Start offloading.
开始拆卸
The crane isn't finished. We got another problem below decks.
起重机还没搭好  甲板下面又有问题了
Pull four men off the welding crew to help tie up the sub.
调四个人到前面来帮忙  快！
My goodness!
我的老天爷！
Daumer Daumer Daumer. Why didn't you hire this person?
多玛  多玛？  你怎么没雇用雷白
Whatever his price would've been it would've been worth it.
不管他价码多高  都值得啊
Bring it up!
拉起来
Ease it over now.
轻轻搬过去  对了
7号  7号  现在
放下  轻点
好了  绑好
There's someone in the water!
水里有人  停
Behind you!
在你后面,
I saw someone in the water!
我看见水里有人
左边
Hook him!
他在那里！
Hook that son of a bitch!
钓他上来  一定能抓到他
这是他的！  好呀
Check for a bomb!
检查船身  他可能放了炸弹
你看到他了吗？
Who saw him? Come on!
谁看到他了？  快！
起火了！  全面戒备
You're incredible.
你真不可思议
It's a shame you're not cooking for us.
可惜你不替我们烧饭
Next thing I know...
另一件我肯定的事
... you'll be dating musicians.
你一定会和跟搞音乐的约会
你在下面干什么？
Where's Daumer?
多玛呢？
Probably dead.
八成死了吧
The bowplane is jammed.
船头卡住了
We can't submerge.
潜不下去
I'll handle it. It'll be operational underway.
我来处理  马上就能动起来
You fix it I'll make you an admiral.
修好的话  升你当上将
Done. Where're you going?
行！  你去哪里？
- Make Honolulu glow in the dark. - Outstanding.
- 点燃檀香山夜空  - 美妙极了
I'll meet you 15 miles due south in the captain's launch.
我和你在15英里以南碰面
Rally your men here in zero one.
一分钟内召集你的人
I need an acetylene torch an arc welder and a crowbar now!
我要电石气火把  焊枪铁把手  快去拿！
- What'd he say? - He can't fix it.
- 他说什么？  - 说他不会修
I'll fix it! Go! Now!
我来修！  去拿工具来
Why can't you speak English?
为什么你不会英文？  去你的
Hang in there.
忍耐一下
Talk to me.
说吧
There's nothing to say.
没什么好说的
Whatever they did...
不管他们是怎么弄的
... they're smarter than I am.
他们显然比我聪明
Everything's dead.
都发动不了
It's hopeless.
没希望了,
Nothing is hopeless. Take heart.
不可能没希望的  要记住
Give me time I'll figure it out.
给我时间  我会解决
I like your attitude. Excellent.
这种态度我喜欢！  很好
It's clear.
甲板安全了
What the hell..?
怎么搞的
I'll put it to you in plain English. It is so simple.
我用简单的英文讲给你听  真的很简单
Hammer that rod into place.
把杆子锤进去,
Weld it over the bowplane. Without it we can't survive.
焊在扇翼上  没有它  我们走不了
Make him understand. Now!
解释给他听  快！
Where's Johnson?
强森呢？
He's gone.
死了
They can't get away with this!
我绝不饶他们
What about the five - inch guns?
5英寸炮能用吗
We offloaded all the armor - piercing rounds. We got starbursts.
夏威夷卸下穿甲弹只剩照明弹
Nothing that will penetrate.
没有攻击性武器可使用
Gunner's mate.
副炮手
See those?
看到没？
We still got shells for those.
我们还有那型的炮弹
I did it.
成功了
It's charging. In a few minutes we'll have power to fire.
开始充电了  几分钟后就能开火了
Well done.
干的好
Let's go!
继续  走
Get on those last three bags!
最后三袋
Out of line.
快点
- Another one. - Watch my hand signals!
- 又一个  - 注意我的手势
Stand clear!
闪开！
Easy guys easy.
轻点！  不急
What's the sub's course and speed?
潜水艇的时速和方位呢？
Course 172. Speed six knots.
172度  时速6海英里
Get down the five - inch guns!
快调整5英寸炮的角度
- What do you want me to do? - See those black switches?
- 我要怎么做？  - 看到黑色开关了吗？
- Click them on one by one. - lf the sub blows won't the nukes go?
- 一个一个推上去  - 如果潜艇爆炸  那核子武器呢
No. They won't detonate.
他们不会爆炸
Just sink with the sub.
只会和船一起沉下去
Lower the cradle.
放支架,
Cradle lowered.
支架放下
- Ram the projectile. - Easy.
- 上飞弹  - 轻点
Ram the powder easy.
轻轻上火药
Real easy!
非常小心
Starbursts are ready.
照明弹准备好了
Fire starburst!
发射照明弹
All right.
来吧,
You secure this room. Get back to work jack - off!
你守住房间  回位子去  笨蛋！
They're firing at us!
他们在打我们
They're just desperate.
困兽之斗罢了
Those are starbursts. They don't have shells to hurt us.
只不过是照明弹  他们没有飞弹能打我们
204 degrees Calaway.
204度  凯拉威
Elevate the barrel.
升炮管
028 degrees.
028度
Fire in the hole.
发射
He's doing it! We're out of time!
他发射了！  我们没时间了
They're reloading right now.
他们在上弹药了,
Granger Tackman! Reload!
赶快！  再上弹药！
Lowering cradle.
放支架,
Scoot over!
快开动
Goddamn!
见鬼
Close the breech.
关后膛
Lower it. Lower the bowplane!
再试试  放低一点  把扇翼放低
Pull! It's working! It's working! Come on let's go.
拉！  成功了！  成功了！  走  咱们走！
241 degrees.
241度,
241 degrees back.
覆述  241度
Dive!
潜下！  关上舱盖！
It's working!
扇翼动了
- 204 degrees. - 204 degrees.
- 204度  - 204度
This is it.
就看这一发
Ryback is gone.
没希望了！
Let me look.
让我看看
Fire in the hole!
发射
- Direct hit! - We hit it!
- 直接命中！  - 我们打中了
What the hell is going on?
怎么搞的
Porky pig. Little red fucker with the mustache.
大肥猪  小红帽长短胡子
史斯
All of my life...
我这一生...
... Saturday morning cartoons.
周末早上的卡通片
The best.
最棒
Shit.
妈的
For example...
例如...
... remember those two little shrimps coming in riding seahorses...
记不记得两只小虾游进海湾？  骑着小海马,
... little chaps little pistols?
戴着小帽  玩小手枪？
Shooting over their shoulders.
朝肩后开枪
Rescue that lobster from the...
救救龙虾
... Swedish cook.
免遭瑞典厨子毒手
Funniest thing I ever saw!
我看过最有意思的东西
- Splendid work by the way. - Strannix!
- 做的好极了  - Strannix
Splendid work!
做的好极了
My my my...
噢  老天爷...
... how hell doth quicken the spirit.
困境激发士气
- Tomahawks! - They're up and ready.
- 战斧飞弹  - 已经准备好了
Where?
在哪里？
- Fire control. - Of course! The fire control.
- 发射台  - 当然是在发射台
Chips and dips on the weather deck.
很快会在甲板上开庆功宴
Motor launch is waiting! All hands!
别晚了  等着发射呢
Clear out of here!
所有人都离开这里！
Let's go.
走吧
Four minutes.
只剩四分钟
Meet us at the motor launch.
在马达房会合！
Four little minutes.
四分钟
Home run.
啊  精彩
We did it!
成功了
This little piggy went to market.
"这只小猪进市场"
This little piggy stayed home.
"这只小猪留在家"
And this little piggy...
剩下这小猪...
Oh mama. Oh mama.
噢  妈妈！  噢  妈妈！  喂...
All the way home!
一路喂...回家
Happy trails.
一路顺风
In the captain's launch there's the MX 20- 20...
雷麦若  有部MX20- 20
... the SEAL magnaphone. Bring it here. Take her with you.
在船长室  拿来给我
The car phone.
带她一起去  什么？  汽车电话
Admiral?
上将！
The Nimitz is tracking two Tomahawks launched from the ship.
尼兹号接收到  密舰发射了两枚战斧飞弹！
- Where're they headed? - Honolulu.
- 目的地？  - 檀香山
Oh God.
老天
- What's the flight time? - 24 minutes sir.
- 要飞多久？  - 二十四分钟
- Can we destroy them in the air? - Destruct codes are on the Missouri.
- 能不能在空中摧毁？  - 密码藏在密舰上
Scramble Navy and Air Force fighters from Pearl.
从珍珠港调海空军特战部队
What are the consequences of missiles dropping on Honolulu?
飞弹在檀香山会引起什么后果
About a million people will reach 10 000 degrees Fahrenheit...
上校？  约一百万人面临华氏一万度
... in less than a second.
全部耗时一秒内
Mr. Secretary...
部长先生...
We'll just blame it on the cook.
一出问题我们就推给厨子
Absolutely.
一定
Take it north.
往北
Roger that. Heading north.
明白  往北
I'll take that weapon.
我来拿那武器
Quietly.
别出声
Now.
现在！
You look familiar.
你很面熟
I know you don't I?
我认识你  对吧？
I think you do.
没错
Been a long time.
好久不见
Yes sir. It has.
可不是
Turn around.
转过身去
We'll have a tour. Step forward.
带你逛逛  往前
Here we have...
这里是...
... our Tomahawks...
我们的战斧飞弹
... speeding their way to the sunny Aloha State. Turn around.
正加速飞往艳阳下的夏威夷  转过去
As you see...
你也看的出
... there will be no return.
战斧是阻止不了的
And I got the key.
而钥匙在我这儿
The lock is broken. Step forward.
锁已经坏了  往前
Sit over there.
坐过去
You'll watch the end of the world on TV.
让你从电视上看着世界毁灭
Put your feet up.
随便坐啊
Relax.
放轻松
You know you're good.
你知道  你本领很好
You are really good.
真的很好
It's a shame to kill you.
杀你真是遗憾
Behold my finest work.
但将是我此生杰作
Do me a favor. Tell me something.
帮个忙  告诉我...
You really think blowing up a bunch of innocent people...
你真的以为杀一群无辜的人...
... will change anything?
就能造成改变吗？
What made you flip like this?
你怎么会变成这样？
I got tired of coming up with desperate solutions...
我不能忍受急如星火的找答案
... to impossible problems created by other people.
来解决其他鸟人所惹的麻烦
All your ridiculous pitiful antics won't change a thing.
你这些可笑又可怜的把戏  绝对于事无补
You and I...
你和我...
... we're puppets in the same sick play.
都是同场戏里的玩偶...
We serve the same master...
伺候着同样的主子...
... and he's an ungrateful lunatic. There's nothing we can do about it.
而他根本不知感激  我们无能为力
You and I are the same.
你和我都一样
No. There's a difference my man.
不  有差别的  兄台
You have faith. I don't.
你有信念  我没有
Keep the faith Strannix.
勇往直前吧  史传尼
Locked on my nose 15 miles.
它被锁定了  只离15英里
Five miles on target. Weapon status clear.
5英里  同步了  随时准备轰炸
Roger.
是
Admiral...
将军
They intercepted one missile.
已栏截飞弹一枚
And the other one?
另外那枚呢,
It slipped through.
漏网而去
Chief...
组长,
... we've only got time for one shot. So we'll do it by the numbers.
只够时间试一次了  所以我们一步步来
Load the disk.
装磁碟片
Now punch 4- 7.
打47
You're now on KU.
你已经接上Ku系统
Code is 6 4...
密码是六  四...
... 3 5...
三  五...
... 0 0.
零  零...
That's 643500. Is my read - back correct?
密码是643500  我覆述的对吗？
Affirmative.
正确
锁定
Stand by.
预备
报废
Got it! Nimitz is no longer tracking.
成了！  尼门不必再追了
Good man Ryback!
干的好  雷白
Sir call off your bombers. Call off your bombers.
长官  调回战斗机  长官
We're calling off the aircraft. We're calling them off.
撤除空中行动  撤除空中部队
Thanks Ryback. Great job! Great job!
谢了  雷白  干的好
Want to go swimming? I got a Zodiac and some C - rays...
想不想游几圈？  我有橡皮小艇和些干粮
... a little umbrella...
还有小阳伞...
I'll go with you.
你办到了  我和你一起去
She's all right! She's all right!
密舰安然无恙！  毫发未损！
Good good all of you guys.
好  好  干的好
Great!
太精彩了
Good job!
胜的漂亮
Hold on in there we'll get you out in a minute!
再忍忍  马上救你们出来
What'd I miss chief?
我错过好戏了
You'll need 3 or 4 stitches. Come to the infirmary.
看来你得缝个三  四针  到医务室来
I'm afraid of needles you know.
我怕针头
- What's for breakfast Case? - Subs Tackman. Subs!
- 早餐吃什么  凯斯？  - 潜水艇三明治
Case show me a move.
凯斯  跳两步吧
Here's one move.
这是一招
Present arms!
敬礼！